Marc Gaede Papers, 1910-1999.: Finding Aid C1436
Manuscripts Division
Marc Gaede Papers
1971-1999
1910-1999
Manuscripts Division
Gaede, Marc
C1436
40 boxes
23.4 linear feet
Marc Gaede (1946- ) is an American photographer, environmental activist, and teacher based in California. The collection consists of Gaede's black-and-white photographs of the American West and Southwest, correspondence, contracts, and other working files primarily related to his books on photography, archaeology, and conservation, and a large group of working files, which include audiovisual and digital materials, for a biography project Gaede collaborated on with Hunkpapa Lakota Sioux activist Robert Sundance (1927-1993).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of black-and-white photographic prints, working files, and correspondence of Marc Gaede, including materials created in collaboration with Marnie Walker Gaede and Robert Sundance, largely related to book projects between the mid 1970s and the late 1990s. Photographic materials include over 250 mounted prints of landscapes and portraits that appeared in photography books published under the Gaedes' Chaco Press, which include Images from the Southwest (1986), Bordertowns (1988), and Images from the Great West (1990), as well as several portraits of friends and family and other images. Working files exist for the same books as well as for Camera, Spade and Pen (1980), The Hopi Photographs (1988), and other published works on archaeology and conservation. These files are comprised of correspondence, publishing contracts and agreements, drafts, image lists, publicity materials, legal and financial documents, sound recordings, and other related materials.
A large portion of the collection consists of working files for Sundance: The Robert Sundance Story (1994), a biography of Lakota Sioux activist Robert Sundance written collaboratively by Sundance and Marc Gaede and edited by Marnie Gaede. The book tells the story of Sundance's struggle with and recovery from alcoholism, his famous court battle against the city and county of Los Angeles to improve the treatment of alcoholics on Skid Row, and his later work as an American Indian rights activist. Working files for this project include sound recordings and transcriptions of Sundance's oral narration, drafts of chapters and the full book in both paper and digital form, as well as publishing correspondence, agreements, and related documents. Also present are extensive research, legal, and publicity files Sundance kept regarding his legal case and other cases involving tribal sovereignty and American Indian rights, as well as personal writings, family documents, photographs, and correspondence of Sundance provided to Gaede as source material.
A small amount of additional correspondence pertains to publishing, as well as to courses Gaede taught on environmentalism, participation in the Sea Shepherd Conservation Society, and other professional activities.
Arrangement
Organized into the following four primary file groups: Photographic Prints; Photography, Archaeology, and Conservation Working Files; Robert Sundance Working Files; and General Correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research. Several folders (housed in Box B-000856) are closed due to the presence of personally identifiable information.
For preservation reasons, physical access to original audio and visual media in a variety of magnetic and optic formats is restricted. The Special Collections does not have playback equipment and facilities, and all original media, especially in obsolete formats, must be digitally remastered or converted in accordance with prevailing preservation standards in order to be safely accessed. Subject to staffial approval, patrons may request duplicates of such original media, but will be responsible for both the cost of digital conversion and the cost of the duplicate, payable in advance. Public Services staff handles all such requests. Depending on the nature of the media, this process can take 4-6 weeks or longer.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Marc and Marnie Gaede in 2012 (AM 2013-55), with an addition in May 2018 (AM 2018-104).
Appraisal
No materials were separated during 2016-2018 processing.
Gaede, Marc
Biographical / Historical
Marc Gaede (1946- ) is an American photographer, environmental activist, and teacher. Born in Tuscon, Arizona, Gaede grew up in Flagstaff, where he immersed himself in the study of field geology, archaeology, and physical anthropology. After returning in 1968 from military service as a U.S. Marine Corps photographer, Gaede became involved in environmental activism. In 1970, he co-founded the early direct action environmental group Black Mesa Defense Fund. In collaboration with members of the American Indian Movement and Edward Abbey (1927-1989), the group organized a direct action campaign against strip mining on shared Navajo and Hopi land on Black Mesa in April 1971. The group's actions inspired Abbey's 1975 novel The Monkey Wrench Gang, along with the next generation of radical environmental advocacy groups, such as Earth First!, who practiced a form of ecological sabotage against environmentally damaging companies and individuals that came to be known as "monkeywrenching." Gaede received his Bachelor of Science degree in anthropology from Northern Arizona University in 1972, and he worked at the at the Museum of Northern Arizona from 1968 to 1977, first as a staff photographer and later as curator of photography. For five months in 1977, he worked for photographer Ansel Adams as a temporary darkroom assistant in Adams's darkroom and studio in Carmel, California. Later he was the Photographer-in-Residence at the University of Arizona's Center for Creative Photography in 1978-1979.
In 1973, Marc Gaede married Marnie Walker Gaede, a writer, editor, publisher, and environmentalist who collaborated with him to edit and publish photography books centering on indigenous cultures and landscapes of the American West and Southwest, many under their own publishing imprint Chaco Press. The Gaedes moved to the Los Angeles area in 1982, where they worked in the television and film industry, including as script analysts for the Walt Disney Company. Gaede received a Master of Fine Arts in photography from the Art Center College of Design in Pasadena in 1988, where he has since worked as an instructor in subjects including photography, environmental issues, and physical anthropology. Since 1989, the Gaedes have also been actively involved with the Sea Shepherd Conservation Society. Marc Gaede joined Sea Shepherd on a 1989 dolphin campaign in Costa Rica as a photographer for Outside magazine and has since photographed numerous high seas campaigns. From 1990 to 1993, the Gaedes worked closely with Robert Sundance, a Lakota Sioux activist from the Standing Rock Indian Reservation, to collaboratively write Sundance's biography.
Alcoholics -- United States -- Civil rights -- Sources.; Environmentalists -- United States -- 20th century -- Sources.; Indians of North America -- Politics and government -- 20th century -- Sources.; Indians of North America -- Social conditions -- 20th century -- Sources.; Indians, Treatment of -- United States -- 20th century -- Sources.; Lakota Indians -- 20th century -- Sources.; Photographers -- West (U.S.) -- 20th century -- Photographs.; Political activists -- United States -- 20th century -- Sources.; Sioux Nation -- 20th century.; West (U.S.) -- 20th century -- Photographs.; Audiocassettes -- 20th century.; Correspondence -- 20th century; Born digital.; Drafts (documents) -- 20th century.; Legal correspondence, American -- 20th century.; Photographs -- 20th century.; Abbey, Edward, 1927-1989.; Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984; Cory, Kate, 1861-1958; Gaede, Marc; Gaede, Marnie; Sundance, Robert, 1927-1993
- Photographic Prints, 1971-1997; 14 boxes
  Arrangement
  Prints are arranged intellectually into file groups by book project or topic, though they are physically housed by size.
  Scope and Contents
  Consists primarily of mounted black-and-white photographs by Marc Gaede for his books Images from the Southwest (1986), Bordertowns (1988), and Images from the Great West (1990). Most photographs depict landscapes in various locations across the American West, Southwest, and northern Mexico; others include portraits of artists, writers, and indigenous people living in these areas. There are also several portraits of Marc and Marnie Gaede with family and friends, including Ansel and Virginia Adams, Beaumont Newhall, and A.B. Guthrie, Jr., as well as several other prints by Marc Gaede that did not appear in his books. Most photographs range from 8x10" to 15x19" in size and are mounted on somewhat larger boards, but twenty-seven large photographs (20x24" prints mounted on 28x34" boards) are also present for Images from the Southwest and Images from the Great West. Photograph titles are usually handwritten by Gaede on the back of mounted prints. When present, these titles were transcribed directly into the finding aid and generally reflect the titles of photographs as they were published in Gaede's books, with minor variations. When no title was present on a print, a title was supplied based on the title of the published image. Some mounted prints have discarded prints of different photographs mounted on the reverse side, which are untitled and often crossed or slashed out.
  - Images from the Southwest, 1971-1997; 6 boxes
    Materials are not arranged according to any arrangement scheme.
    Consists of mounted 8x10", 11x14", 15x19", and 20x24" photographs that appeared in Images from the Southwest (Chaco Press, 1986). They primarily depict landscapes in Arizona, New Mexico, southern Utah, Colorado, Nevada, and Sonora, Mexico, as well as portraits of indigenous people and other authors and artists living in those areas.
    - Spruce Tree House, Mesa Verde, Colorado, undated; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 1)
    - Walpi, Arizona, 1978; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 2)
      Printed 1986.
    - Moencopi, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 3)
      Reproduction print.
    - Burned Trees, Canyon de Chelly, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 4)
      Printed 1985. Reproduction print.
    - Aqathlan, Kayenta, Arizona, 1985 November; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 5)
    - Bakes Dry Lake Bed, 1986 February; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 6)
      First print.
    - Winter Sunrise, Professor Valley, Utah, undated; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 7)
      Printed 1977.
    - Ophir Mountains, Colorado, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 8)
    - Southern Hopi Buttes, undated; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 9)
    - Little Colorado River Gorge, Arizona, 1983-1984; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 10)
      Printed 1986. Reproduction print.
    - Mormon House, Buff, Utah, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 11)
    - Baboquivari Peak, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 12)
    - Mission Cabosca, 1986 January; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 13)
    - Fishermen's Graves, Baja, California, 1971; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 14)
    - Canyons in Canyon de Chelly, undated; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 15)
    - Abbot Sekaquaptewa, undated; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 16)
    - Church on East Side of Janos Chihuahua, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 17)
    - Canyon de Chelly, 1977; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 18)
    - Wagon and Hogan Valley, Arizona, 1976; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 19)
    - Sliprock, New Mexico, 1974; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 20)
    - Saguros and Choya, Ajo Mountains, 1985 December; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 21)
      Printed 1985.
    - Cinder Hills Near Sunset, Crater, Arizona, 1978; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 22)
    - Garnet P. First Mesa, Arizona, 1976; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 23)
    - Corsal In Snow, San Juan Mountains, 1986 January; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 24)
      Printed 1986. First print.
    - The Trail to White House, undated; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 25)
    - Mission Cocóspera, Sonora, Mexico, 1985 February; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 26)
    - Black Mountains, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 27)
    - Navajo Mountain from West Side, 1986 March; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 28)
      Reproduction Print
    - Taos Pueblo, New Mexico, 1974; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 29)
    - Taos Pueblo, New Mexico, circa 1973; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 32)
    - Fred Kabotie, Second Mesa, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 30)
    - Miner's Camp, Oatman, Arizona, 1983; 1 item (Box P-000061, Item 31)
    - Storm over Pueblo Bonito, Chaco Canyon, New Mexico, 1971; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 1)
      Printed 1971. Inscription on reverse side: "Best print of this shot."
    - Canyon de Chelly, Arizona, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 2)
    - Hogan and Clouds, Nitsin Valley, Arizona, 1976; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 3)
    - The Nankoweap Meets the Colorado, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 4)
    - Chinde (Ghost) Hogan, Nitsin Valley, Arizona, 1976; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 5)
    - Marble Canyon, Grand Canyon, 1985 March; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 6)
    - Needle Mountains and Colorado River, Arizona, 1985 June; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 7)
    - Hacienda de San Diego de Louis Tessa, Chihuahua, Mexico, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 8)
    - Trail to White House, 1977; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 9)
    - Junction of Colorado and Little Colorado Rivers, 1986 March; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 10)
    - Zion Canyon, 1986 March; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 11)
    - Canyons in Canyon de Chelly, 1977; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 12)
    - Manuel Kooyahoema, Hotevilla, Arizona, 1985 August; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 13)
      Printed 1985. First print.
    - Sunset Crater, 1978; 1 item (Box P-000062, Item 14)
    - Ansel Adams and Allen Ross, Carmel, California, 1977; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 1)
    - Ansel Adams and Allen Ross, Carmel, California, 1977; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 2)
    - Father Keno Remains - Magdalena, Mexico, 1985; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 3)
    - Marvin and Bobby - Flying "M" Ranch, 1981 October; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 4)
    - Marvin and Bobby - Flying "M" Ranch, 1981 October; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 5)
    - Georgie White Clark - Lake Mead, Nevada, 1986 April; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 6)
      Reproduction Print.
    - Bates Wilson, Utah, 1973; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 7)
      Reproduction Print. Printed 1986.
    - Vera Pooyuma - Hotevilla, Arizona, 1980; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 8)
      Printed 1980.
    - Bientien Yazz at Wide Ruins, Arizona, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 9)
    - R.C. Gorman, Taos, New Mexico, 1982 October; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 10)
      Includes a discarded version of the same print on the reverse side.
    - R.C. Gorman, Taos, New Mexico, 1982; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 11)
    - Peter McDonald - Gallup, 1982 August; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 12)
    - Charles Loloma - Hotevilla, Arizona, 1980; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 13)
    - Charles Loloma, circa 1977; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 14)
    - Sun Chief, Don Talyesua, Oraibi, Arizona, 1972; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 15)
    - Sun Chief, Oraibi, Arizona, 1972; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 16)
    - Harrison Begay, Navajo Painter, Continental Hotel, Arizona, 1975; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 17)
    - Frank Waters at Home, Tucson, 1985 April; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 18)
      First Print.
    - Dog at Taos, New Mexico, circa 1973; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 19)
    - Georgie White Clark, Lake Mead, Nevada, 1986 April; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 20)
    - Bruce Babbitt, Phoenix, 1986 June; 1 item (Box P-000063, Item 21)
    - Altar at Cocóspera, 1985; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 1)
    - The Mittens in Snow, 1983; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 2)
    - Horses in Muerto, Arizona, 1997; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 3)
      Image undated (printed in 1997).
    - The Mittens from Old Campground, Monument Valley, 1983; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 4)
    - Mount Wilson Range, Colorado, 1986; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 5)
    - The Lower Valley, Monument Valley, Arizona, 1984; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 6)
      Printed 1989.
    - Corrals in Snow, 1986; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 7)
    - Marble Canyon and the Colorado River, Arizona, 1986; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 8)
      Imaged undated (printed 1986).
    - Old Wagon and Shed, El Vale, New Mexico, 1991; 1 item (Box Z-000001, Item 9)
      Image undated (printed 1991).
    - Ophir Mountains from Ophir Pass, Colorado, 1985; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 1)
    - San Francisco Peaks, Arizona, 1983; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 2)
    - Bajada of the Ajos, 1987; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 3)
      Image undated (printed 1987).
    - Hopi Salt Rocks, Moenavi, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 4)
    - La Sal Mountains from Dead Horse Point, Canyonlands, Utah, 1985; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 5)
    - The Yeibichai, Monument Valley, 1992; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 6)
      Image undated (printed 1992).
    - San Xavier del Bac, Tuscon, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 7)
    - Navajo Petroglyphs Near Rock Point, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 8)
    - Needle Mountains and Colorado River, 1985; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 9)
    - The Southern Hopi Buttes, Arizona, 1985; 1 item (Box Z-000002, Item 10)
    - Taos Pueblo, New Mexico, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 1)
      Printed 1984.
    - Mine and Tailings - Ophir, Colorado, 1985 August; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 2)
    - Goosenecks of the San Juan, 1984 January; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 3)
    - Old Wagon and Shed, El Valle, New Mexico, 1984 October; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 4)
      Printed December 1984.
    - The Yeibichai, Monument Valley, Arizona, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 5)
    - Spanish Peaks - Colorado, 1985 June; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 6)
      1st print.
    - San Francisco Peaks from Grey Mountain, Arizona, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 7)
    - Kin Bineola - Chaco Canyon, New Mexico, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 8)
    - The Mittens in Snow, Monument Valley, Arizona, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 9)
    - Monument Valley, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 10)
    - Hogan and Three Sisters - Monument Valley, 1984; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 11)
    - Trail to White House, Canyon de Chelly, Arizona, 1978; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 12)
    - The Mittens, 1983; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 13)
    - Mummy Cave - Canyon del Muerto, Arizona, 1975; 1 item (Box P-000083, Item 14)
  - Bordertowns, 1980 March-1987; 2 boxes
    Consists of mounted 8x10" photographs that appeared in Bordertowns (Chaco Press, 1988), primarily depicting people struggling with alcoholism and violence in towns bordering the Hopi, Navajo, and Ute reservations in the Four Corners region of the United States where Arizona, Utah, Colorado, and New Mexico meet. Many photographs were taken in Gallup, New Mexico.
    - Winslow, 1986 November; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 1)
    - They Are In Love - Palmino Club - Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 2)
    - Guards at Milan's Club - Gallup, New Mexico, undated; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 3)
    - Sammy - Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 4)
    - Trader's, Gallup, 1987 August; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 5)
      Includes a discarded print of warning signs for the Petrified Forest National Monument.
    - Jasper - Prairie Moon Tavern - Winslow, Arizona, 1980 April; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 6)
    - Behind the Chutes - Gallup, 1981 August; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 7)
    - Sign - Gallup, 1987 August; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 8)
      Includes a discarded print on the reverse side of a man drinking in an alley between two buildings.
    - Gallup, 1984 August; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 9)
      Includes a discarded print on the reverse side of two police officers leaning against a Gallup police car.
    - Holbrook, Arizona, 1982 March; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 10)
      Reproduction Print. Includes a discarded print of the exterior of the boarded-up office building of The Navajo Outlook.
    - Winslow, Arizona, 1980 September; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 11)
    - Joey - Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 12)
    - Joey - Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 13)
    - Ray - Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 14)
    - Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 15)
    - Wrecking Yard - Gallup, undated; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 16)
    - Mexican Hat, Utah, 1982 May; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 17)
    - Crusing, Taylor Todachine and Michael Tom, Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 18)
    - Gary Charley's Grave, Bita Hotchee, Arizona, 1982 October; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 19)
    - Chief Theater - Gallup, New Mexico, 1981 January; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 20)
    - Mexican Hat, Utah, 1980 July; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 21)
    - Rodeo Crowd - Gallup, 1987 August; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 22)
      Includes a discarded print of the boarded-up office building of The Navajo Outlook.
    - Gray Mountain, Arizona, 1980 August; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 23)
    - Barrel Racing - Gallup, Ceremonial Rodeo, 1987 August; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 24)
      Includes a discarded photograph of a warning sign on the reverse side.
    - Red Power Grafitti - Fort Defiance, Arizona, 1981 April; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 25)
    - In the American Bar, Gallup, 1987 August; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 26)
      Includes a discarded print of police officers leading a Native American man into the back of a police van on the reverse side.
    - Stealing His Boots, Flagstaff, 1980 March; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 27)
    - Farmington, New Mexico, 1982 May; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 28)
    - Mission at Grey Mountain, 1981 March; 1 item (Box P-000064, Item 29)
    - The Big Tank, Drunk Tank - Gallup, 1982 August; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 1)
    - Sundown Drink - Holbrook, undated; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 2)
    - Wrong Way on the Freeway Near Gallup, 1987 June; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 3)
      Includes a discarded print of a portrait of a man standing near a post.
    - Passed Out in Winslow, undated; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 4)
      Includes a discarded print of a train yard on the reverse side.
    - Gary Charley, Dead of Exposure, Farmington, New Mexico (1981), 1987; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 5)
      1981 photograph from the State of New Mexico Medical Examiner's Office copied from 35mm half frame slide by Marc Gaede in 1987.
    - "One Step Closer and I'll Jump!", PHS, Gallup, 1987 August; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 6)
    - But He Lives to Sleep There, Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 7)
    - Dying Words / Nearly Dead in Front of the Rosetree Bar, Flagstaff, 1980 April; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 8)
    - No Pictures, No Pictures!, Gallup, New Mexico, undated; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 9)
    - Navajo Outlook - Holbrook, Arizona, 1981 June; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 10)
    - He May Not Make It!, Gallup, 1987 August; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 11)
      Includes a discarded print of a pile of junked truck bodies on the reverse side.
    - Gary Charlie - Moenkopi, Arizona, 1981 January; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 12)
    - Slashed in Face - Commercial Club - Gallup, 1982 October; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 13)
    - Those People Killed the Last One They Rolled - Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 14)
    - They Stabbed Him in the Chest, Gallup, 1986 July; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 15)
    - Gary Charlie, 1980 March; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 16)
    - Passed Out in the Truck, Gallup, 1986 October; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 17)
    - Run over by a Drunk, Gallup, undated; 1 item (Box P-000065, Item 18)